LISA SHAY

(+44) 07858625722 | jyhsieh00@outlook.com Eligible to work in the United Kingdom without sponsorship LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiunyu-hsieh/ Personal Website: https://jiunyu-hsieh.github.io/Lisashay.github.io/

Summary

I have recently completed my Masters Degree from the University of Warwick, following achievement of a bachelor's degree in finance engineering. During these courses, I developed a solid foundation in statistics and modelling. I have developed a passion for data analysis, which started when I ran my own marketing studio and worked in the e-commerce industry. Here, I leveraged data insights to determine the most profitable products. Since then, I have independently learned and gained certifications in different analytical tools such as Alteryx, SQL, Python and Tableau. To further hone these skills, I challenged myself by undertaking practical projects using these tools. Examples include a customer retention / supermarket analysis project and an interactive dashboard to choose appropriate ski resorts.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF WARWICK-United Kingdom

Oct 2022-Sep 2023

Master of Science, Supply Chain and Logistics Management (Expected: Merit)

Majors: Procurement and Inventory Management, Storage and Warehousing Techniques, Transport Techniques and Management

EAST CHINA NORMAL UNIVERSITY - China

Sep 2018-Jun 2022

Bachelor of Economics, Finance Engineering (2:1)

Majors: Advanced Excel Application, Mathematical Statistics, Time Series, Econometrics, Multivariate Statistical Analysis

Skills & Certifications

- Alteryx (Alteryx Designer Advanced): Data Cleaning, Regex, Transpose, CrossTab, Spatial
- SQL (HackerRank Advanced Certificate): MySQL
- Tableau: Filters, Parameters, Calculated Fields
- Excel (Microsoft Excel 2019 Expert): VLookup, HLookup, Pivot Table, VBA
- Python: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Sklearn

Work Experience & Volunteering

CHEYLESMORE GOOD NEIGHBOURS - Volunteer - Learnington Spa, UK

Feb 2023 – Sep 2023

Provided one-on-one assistance to the elderly in the use of smart devices by simplifying technical concepts and creating step-bystep instructions tailored for each individual to reference.

TINGHSIN INTERNATIONAL GROUP - Operation Intern - Shanghai, China

Jun 2021 - Sep 2021

- Managed 44 group chats by producing answer templates and SOP documents, reducing client complaints rate by 5.34%.
- Tailored push notifications through user profiling based on product preference, resulting in a 20% increase in repeat purchase rate.
- Designed dashboards to monitor key business metrics, leveraging insights to provide operation recommendations, driving a 17% increase in conversion rate.

WELLEM MEDICAL GROUP - Data Clerk Intern - Shanghai, China

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Utilised advanced Excel functions, including VLOOKUP and nested IF statements to cross reference monthly finance statements with **20,000** records for 8 clinics across 4 payment channels.
- Automated Excel sheet creation with **Python** (pandas), ensuring both data accuracy and efficiency.

Projects

SKI RESORT SELECTOR DASHBOARD - Personal Project (Skills utilised: Alteryx, SQL, Excel, Tableau)

Jun 2023

I conducted data cleaning and transformation to design an interactive dashboard to assist people in selecting ideal ski resorts based on their specific requirements.

- Implemented Regex, Transform and Spatial Tools within Alteryx to analyse geographical data with over 800,000 records.
- Utilised SQL to extract and transform data into usable formats for downstream analysis and visualisation in Tableau.

SUPERMARKET MARKETING ANALYSIS – Personal Project (Skills utilised: Alteryx, Python, Excel, Tableau)

Apr 2023

For this project, I aimed to identify customers with the highest buying potential using a machine learning model based on an analysis of a marketing campaign conducted with a 10% customer base sample.

- Used data cleansing in Alteryx to ensure data integrity, including changing data formats and imputing missing data.
- Performed Logistical Regression in Python (pandas, numpy & sklearn) to predict customer purchase choice with 81% accuracy.
- Utilized Excel Pivot Tables and VBA macros for KPI Analysis to maximise profits and optimise market penetration strategies.

CUSTOMER CHURN ANALYSIS – Personal Project (Skills utilised: SOL, Tableau, Figma)

Feb 2023

I conducted an in-depth exploratory analysis to identify the underlying factors contributing to customer churn for Maven Telecom, including creating high-risk customer profiles, and provided 6 recommendations to enhance customer retention.

- Used **SOL** queries to create new fields and tables from a customer database containing 7000+ records and 39 fields.
- Transformed and filtered data by using Aggregating Functions, Case When and CTE to improve the code efficiency.
- Created a wireframe in Figma and visualised data in Tableau to identify key insights to retain customers.

Other

Languages: Chinese, English

Hobbies: In my spare time I enjoy going snowboarding, climbing and running. I most relaxed when I am drawing or improving my cooking skills.